Okay. So, let's think about what we need to change to make this simulate
好了 现在我们来想想要怎么修改
a full yahtzee rolling system with five dice instead of just three.
才能让这个程序完全模拟快艇骰子的机制 采用五个骰子而非三个
Well, first, we need to declare those two variables,
首先 我们需要声明这两个变量
dice four and dice five,
dice4 和 dice5
and we set them by calling the function rollDice.
然后调用 rollDice 函数分别给它们赋值
So now, we call this function rollDice five times simulating five different dice.
现在 我们调用了五次这个 rollDice 函数来模拟五个不同的骰子
And again, inside the while loop,
与之前一样 在 while 循环里
we call them five times updating the variables dice four and dice five as well.
我们也要调用这些函数五次 对变量 dice4 和 dice5 进行更新
Every time we roll all five dice,
我们每掷一次五颗骰子
we update our count variable by one,
就要给变量 count 加 1
because it means one single roll for all the five dice.
因为我们是同时投掷了五颗骰子
And lastly, we need to update our while loop condition here.
最后 我们需要更新这整个 while 循环的条件
So instead of just checking if dice one is the same as dice
所以现在不只要判断 dice1 是否等于 dice2
two and dice two is the same as dice three,
且 dice2 是否等于 dice3
we also check that dice three is the same as dice
我们还需判断 dice3 是否等于 dice4
four and dice four is the same as dice five.
且 dice4 是否等于 dice5
All that is surrounded by these parentheses that have a not signed before it,
所有条件都由这些括号括起 括号前有个表示“非”的符号
which means the while would continue to loop as long as this is not true,
也就意味着只要条件非真 while 循环就会一直执行下去
which means as long as the five dice are not a match.
也就是说只要五颗骰子点数没有完全相同 循环就会一直执行
Notice that I didn't have to say explicitly that dice
注意 我不需要特地说明
five is the same as dice two because that is implicit.
dice5 等于 dice2 因为这是个隐含条件
If that condition happens and
如果这个条件成立了
the condition happens and that condition happens and that condition happens,
这个成立了 这个成立了 这个也成立了
that implicitly saying that all five dice are a match.
那就意味着五个骰子点数都相同
Also, on a small side note,
顺便提一句
notice how I had this written in two lines instead of just one.
注意我把这个写成了两行 而不是一行
This is just to make it easier to read.
这只是为了增强可读性
Usually, it's okay to put new lines in
通常来说 在 Java 里 指令是可以拆行的
the middle of commands in Java as long as it doesn't
只要别把它拆散就好
break the command and it's generally used to make it easier to read, not harder.
通常这么做是为了增强可读性 而不是降低
So for now, don't worry about if you have to write long commands in one single line.
所以目前的话 如果你不得不把长指令写成一行 那也不必担心
But as a side note,
这只是个小建议
you can do something like this.
告诉你可以像我这样做而已